So what I want to try to do is tell a quick story
حسناً ما احاول القيام به هو اخبار قصة قصيرة
about a 404 page and a lesson that was learned as a result of it.
حول صفحة 404 والدرس المستفاد منها
But to start it probably helps to have an understanding
لكن لكي أبدأ ،رُبما قد يساعد فهم
of what a 404 page actually is.
ما هي صفحة 404
The 404 page is that.
صفحة 404 هي
It's that broken experience on the Web.
هي التجربة الفاشلة في موقع الانترنت
It's effectively the default page
هي فعليا الصفحة الافتراضية
when you ask a website for something and it can't find it.
التي تظهر عندما تطلب صفحة لا يمكن العثور عليها
And it serves you the 404 page.
فتظهر لك صفحة 404
It's inherently a feeling of being broken when you go through it.
هو بشكل طبيعي الشعور بكونك قد فشلت اثناء تقدمك
And I just want you to think a little bit about, remember for yourself,
واريدكم ان تفكروا قليلا حولها ,تذكروا انفسكم
it's annoying when you hit this thing.
من المزعج وصولك لهذا الشيء
Because it's the feeling of a broken relationship.
لانه شعور بعلاقة فاشلة
And that's where it's actually also interesting to think about,
وذلك حقا مثير للاهتمام للتفكير به ايضا
where does 404 come from?
من اين تأتي صفحة 404؟
It's from a family of errors actually --
انها في الواقع من عائلة الاخطاء
a whole set of relationship errors,
مجموعة كاملة من اخطاء العلاقات
which, when I started digging into them,
والتي عندما بدأت البحث فيها
it looks almost like a checklist for a sex therapist or a couples counselor.
بدت كما لو أنها قائمة لمعالج جنسي او مستشار ازواج
You sort of get down there to the bottom and things get really dicey.
ذلك يشبه نزولك الى مستويات متدنية الى الاسفل حيث تصبح الاشياء مشبوهة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Yes.
نعم
But these things are everywhere.
لكن هذه الاشياء في كل مكان
They're on sites big, they're on sites small.
في بعض المواقع تكون كبيرة وفي بعض المواقع تكون صغيرة
This is a global experience.
وتحدث في كل مكان في العالم
What a 404 page tells you
مالذي تخبرك به صفحة 404
is that you fell through the cracks.
انك تسقط من خلال الشقوق
And that's not a good experience
وتلك تجربة غير جيدة
when you're used to experiences like this.
عندما كنت معتاد على مثل هذه الخبرات
You can get on your Kinect
يمكنك الجلوس الى جهاز "كينكت" خاصتك
and you can have unicorns dancing
ويمكنك الرقص رقصة وحيد القرن
and rainbows spraying out of your mobile phone.
والون قوس قزح تنتشر من هاتفك المحمول
A 404 page is not what you're looking for.
الصفحة 404 هو ما لا تبحث عنه
You get that, and it's like a slap in the face.
تتلقاها كالصفعة على الوجه
Trying to think about how a 404 felt,
تحاول تخيل ما هو شعور 404
and it would be like if you went to Starbucks
وهو يبدو كما لو أنك ذهبت الى ستار بكس
and there's the guy behind the counter
وها هو الرجل خلف المنضدة
and you're over there and there's no skim milk.
وانت واقف هناك ولا يوجد حليب مقشود
And you say, "Hey, could you bring the skim milk?"
وتقول "من فضلك احضرلي بعض الحليب المقشود"
And they walk out from behind the counter and they've got no pants on.
فيتحركون من خلف المنضدة ويتضح انهم لا يلبسون بناطيل
And you're like, "Oh, I didn't want to see that."
ويكون لسان حالك " لا ,ليس هذا ما اريد رؤيته."
That's the 404 feeling.
هذا هو شعور 404
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I mean, I've heard about that.
اعني انني قد سمعت بذلك
So where this comes into play and why this is important
اذاً ما علاقة كل هذا ولماذا هو مهم
is I head up a technology incubator,
لقد ترأست حاضنة تكنولوجيا
and we had eight startups sitting around there.
ولدينا ثمان شركات ناشئة جالسة هناك
And those startups are focused on what they are, not what they're not,
وهذه الشركات تركز على ما هم عليه وليس على ما ليسوا عليه
until one day Athletepath,
حتى في احد الايام موقع "اثيلي باث"
which is a website that focuses on services for extreme athletes,
وهو موقع يركز على الرياضيين المميزين
found this video.
وجد هذا الفيديو
(Video) Guy: Joey!
(مقطع فيديو) رجل: جوي!
Crowd: Whoa!
الجمهور:هوها
Renny Gleeson: You just ... no, he's not okay.
ريني جليسون. انت فقط... لا, انه ليس بخير
They took that video and they embedded it in their 404 page
اخذوا ذلك المقطع وادمجوه في صفحة 404 الخاصة بهم
and it was like a light bulb went off for everybody in the place.
وكان كالمصباح اشع على كل الحضور في المكان
Because finally there was a page
لانه اخيراً يوجد هناك صفحة
that actually felt like what it felt like to hit a 404.
تبين ما هو شعور الوصول الى صفحة 404
(Laughter)
( ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So this turned into a contest.
وذلك تحول الى مسابقة
Dailypath that offers inspiration
موقع "دايلي باث" التي يقدم الافكار الملهمة
put inspiration on their 404 page.
وضعوا الهاما في صفحة 404 الخاصة بهم
Stayhound, which helps you find pet sitters through your social network,
موقع " ستاي هوند" الذي يساعدك على ايجاد جليس لحيوانك من خلال شبكات التواصل الاجتماعي,
commiserated with your pet.
تفاعل مع حيوانك.
Each one of them found this.
كل واحد منهم وجد هذا
It turned into a 24-hour contest.
تحول الى مسابقة على مدار الاربع وعشرين ساعه
At 4:04 the next day, we gave out $404 in cash.
في الساعة 4:04 في اليوم التالي وزعنا 404 دولار نقداً
And what they learned
وما تعلموه
was that those little things, done right, actually matter,
ان تلك الاشياء الصغيرة اذا عملت بشكل متقن فان لها تأثير,
and that well-designed moments can build brands.
واللحظات المصممة بشكل جيد تصنع علامة تجارية
So you take a look out in the real world,
اذاً عند النظر على العالم الحقيقي,
and the fun thing is you can actually hack these yourself.
الشيء الممتع انك يمكنك اختراقه بمفردك
You can type in an URL and put in a 404 and these will pop.
يمكنك كتابة عنوان انترنت ,والذهاب الى 404 وسوف يظهر لك ذلك
This is one that commiserates with you.
تلك الصفحة التي سوف تواسيك
This is one that blames you.
وتلك التي تلومك
This is one that I loved.
وهذه التي احببت
This is an error page,
وهذه صفحة خاطئة
but what if this error page was also an opportunity?
لكن ماذا لو كانت هذه الصفحة عبارة عن فرصة
So it was a moment in time
اذاً هي لحظة من الوقت
where all of these startups had to sit and think
حيث كان على هذه الشركات الناشئة الجلوس والتفكير
and got really excited about what they could be.
ولقد شعروا بحماس حيال ما يمكنهم ان يكونوا عليه
Because back to the whole relationship issue,
لانه بالعودة الى موضوع العلاقة
what they figured out through this exercise
الذي استنتجوه من خلال هذا التمرين
was that a simple mistake can tell me what you're not,
ان الاخطاء الصغيرة تخبرني مالذي لا تكونه
or it can remind me of why I should love you.
او تذكرني لماذا يجب ان احبك
Thank you.
شكراً
(Applause)
(تصفيق)